University of Washington, Department of Political Science, Box 353530, Seattle, WA 98195.

Jeffrey B. Arnold

I am an Assistant Professor of Political Science a and Core Faculty Member in the Center for Statistics and the Social Sciences at the University of Washington. My research applies statistical and machine learning methods to political science applications. My primary substantive area of research is in the quantitative analysis of war dynamics using event, text, and financial market data. My methodological research focuses on Bayesian statistical methods, particularly I completed my Ph.D. in Political Science at the University of Rochester. Previously, I was an Instructor of Political Science and a Pre-doctoral Fellow at the QuanTM Institute at Emory University. Prior to graduate school worked as a research associate in the Money and Payments Studies research group at the Federal Reserve Bank of New York.

Employment

University of Washington

- Acting Assistant Professor of Political Science, September 2014–present
- Core Faculty Member of the Center for Statistics and the Social Sciences, September 2014–*present*

Emory University

• Instructor of Political Science, September 2013-August 2014

Federal Reserve Bank of New York

- Economist, Money and Payments Studies Function, 2007
- Assistant Economist, Money and Payments Studies Function, 2005–2006
- Research Associate, Payments Studies Function, 2004–2005

Education

University of Rochester

- Ph.D. in Political Science, December 2015
- M.A. in Political Science, March 2012
- Dissertation: Three Essays on Conflict and Financial Markets, and Political Methodology

Dartmouth College

• B.A. in Economics, and Government; *cum laude*; High Honors in Economics, June 2004

Publications

Kimmo Soramäki, Morten L. Bech, Jeffrey Arnold, Robert J. Glass, and Walter E. Beyeler "The Topology of Interbank Payment Flows," *Federal Reserve Bank of New York Staff Reports*, no. 243 (Mar 2006), http://www.newyorkfed.org/research/staff_reports/sr243. html.

Olivier Armantier, Jeffrey B. Arnold, and James J. McAndrews "Changes in the Timing Distribution of Fedwire Funds Transfers," *Federal Reserve Bank of New York Economic Policy Review*, 2008, http://www.newyorkfed.org/research/epr/o8v14n2/o8o9arma.html.

Conference Presentations

PolMeth, Houston, TX, July 21–23, 2016.

Annual Meeting of the Midwest Political Science Association, Chicago, IL, April 7–12, 2016: "Ideology, Appointments, and Battlefield Outcomes", "Bayesian Change Points and Linear Filtering with Shrinkage Priors".

2015 Meeting of the Peace Science Society, Oxford, MS, November 12, 2015. The American Civil War and International Relations workshop.

2014 Meeting of the Peace Science Society, Philadelphia, PA, October 9, 2014. Empirical Implications of the Bargaining Model workshop.

Annual Meeting of the American Political Science Association, Chicago, IL, August 30, 2013.

PolMeth, Charlottesville, VA, July 18, 2013. "Modeling Changepoints by Time-Varying Parameters and Sparse Priors" (poster)

Annual Meeting of the Midwest Political Science Association, Chicago, IL, April 12, 2013: "Pricing the Costly Lottery: Financial Market Reactions to Battlefield Events in the American Civil War", "Producing Death: Estimating the Offense-Defense Balance from the Production Function of Battle Casualties".

2011 Meeting of the Peace Science Society, Savannah, GA, October 26, 2012: "Pricing the Costly Lottery: Financial Market Reactions to Battlefield Events in the American Civil War"

PolMeth, Raleigh, NC, 2012, July 19: "Pricing the Costly Lottery: Financial Market Reactions to Battlefield Events in the American Civil War" (poster)

Annual Meeting of the Midwest Political Science Association, Chicago, IL, April 12–13, 2012: "Who Does History Remember? Using Wikipedia to Measure the Historical Reputation of Leaders", "Producing Death: Modeling and Estimating the Technology of Conflict".

2011 Meeting of the Peace Science Society, Los Angeles, CA, October 15, 2011: "Pricing the Costly Lottery: Financial Market Reactions to Battlefield Events in the American Civil War"

2011 Meeting of the American Political Science Association, Seattle, WA, September 2, 2011: "Destruction or Revelation? Estimating the Influence of Battles on Financial Market Expectations during the the American Civil War" (poster).

Honors & Awards

QuanTM Pre-doctoral Fellow, QuanTM Institute for Quantitative Theory and Methods, Emory University, January–May 2013

Star Lab Poster gAward, The Star Lab, University of Rochester

Star Lab Best Conference Presentation, The Star Lab, University of Rochester, 2011–2012 APSA 2011 Annual Meeting Graduate Student Travel Grant, APSA

Graduate Student Teaching Award, Department of Political Science, University of Rochester, 2011

Sproull Fellowship, University of Rochester, 2007–2009

John Carroll International Economics Scholar Prize for Outstanding Contribution, 2004 James O. Freedman Presidential Scholar, Dartmouth College, 2004

War and Peace Studies Fellow, John Sloan Dickey Center, Dartmouth College, 2003–2004 James O. Freedman Presidential Scholar Research Assistant, Dartmouth College, 2002–2003

Professional & Departmental Service

Software Carpentry Certified Instructor, 2016– Organizer Center for Statistics and the Social Sciences (CSSS) Seminar, 2014–2016

- International Studies Association (ISA) 2014 Working Group, "Forecasting International Events", sponsored by The Scientific Study of International Processes Section (SSIP). With Curtis Signorino.
- Summer Workshop on Analysis of Military Operations and Strategy (SWAMOS). Saltzman Institute for War and Peace Studies, Columbia University, 2012.
- Reviewer for Conflict Management and Peace Science, International Interactions, International Studies Quarterly
- Member of the American Political Science Society, Midwest Political Science Society, Peace Science Society, and the Society for Political Methodology.

Software

ggthemes: R package with extra themes, scales and geoms for ggplot2. pollstR: R client for the HuffingtonPost Pollster API. An ROpenGov package.